VIGNESH RAVI

Choolaimedu, Chennai | Phone: +91 9176074946 | vigneshraviav@gmail.com

Summary

Accomplished Electronic and Communications Engineer with strong communication and leadership skills. A self-learner workaholic who is highly motivated to demonstrate the learned skills and be a part of an organization that provides mutual growth and learning opportunities. Adaptable and ethical towards the working environment and acts as a team player.

Skills

- Customer service experience
- Taking responsibility
- Handling customer complaints
- Acting with urgency
- Critical Thinking
- Persuasive speaking skills
- Team Player
- Highly flexible
- Self and fast learner

Languages/Software Known

- · Python
- Jquery
- Javascript
- HTML
- CSS
- Adobe Photoshop
- · Adobe Premier Pro
- FreshService
- Postman
- Google Scripts

Experience

Technical Account Manager

March 2019 to Current

Freshworks - Freshservice - Chennai, India

- Being point of contact for accounts as a Technical Account Manager
- Handling all escalations relating to the product bugs and issues
- Propose and implement solutions to the customer to optimise Freshservice to its maximum depending on their business requirement.
- Identify and escalate priority issues per Client specifications.
- Follow up and make scheduled call-backs to customers where necessary.
- Work along with product management team to propose product enhancement requests and prioritize bug fixes.
- Customizing end user portals of the product using HTML, JAVA, CSS as per client requirement.
- Building integrations when needed with third party apps via API as per the client's business needs

Product Specialist

October 2020 to Current

Freshworks - Freshrelease - Chennai, India

- Along with Freshservice I was tasked to create a support team along with a few others from my team for Freshrelease - our new agile project management tool.
- Support the product and adopt best practices from Freshservice support

Technical Support Engineer

Jun 2018 to Nov 2018

Sitel India - Bell Canada - Chennai, India

- Interact with customers to provide and process information in response to inquiries, concerns, and requests about products and services.
- Diagnose and resolve technical hardware and software issues involving internet connectivity, email clients, IPTV, VOIP and more

Education and Training

Bachelors in Electronics and Communication Engineering SRM Easwari Engineering College — Chennai, India

April 2018

High School - Computer Science St. Vincent's Matriculation Higher Sec School - Chennai, India April 2014

Accomplishments

- Won multiple awards for having exceptional key KPIs Freshworks India
- Built a script library using Python and Freshservice APIs to carry out mundane tasks thereby off-loading work from Devops Team - Freshworks India
- Rated "Champion" for the year 2019's performance appraisal Freshworks India
- Mentored three junior engineers and helped them maintain their key KPIs

Training and Certifications

- AWS Cloud practitioner essentials certification
- Certified Wireless Network Administrator
- Developer level Python programming
- Digital Marketing fundamentals

Personal Projects

- Agent load bot -A Slackbot to trigger a message in channel when an agent hits the ticket limit for the day using Python and end user support tool APIs
- Script Library A script library using Python/Javascript and Freshservice APIs to carry out mundane tasks thereby off-loading work from Devops Team
- **Personal website** Done with HTML5, CSS3 and Javascript https://iam-vignesh.github.io/my-personal-website/ (mobile and web experience will differ)

Portfolios and Extra-Curricular Activities

- Blog Let's talk Men's Style https://letstalkmenstyle.home.blog
- Site https://iam-vignesh.github.io/my-personal-website/
- Github Repository https://github.com/iam-vignesh/fs_GET_repository
- Short film Best Director Award, Film Appreciation club, Ethiraj College
- Freelance Publicity Designer Elgo Learnings
- Freelance Graphic Designer
- Freelance Content Writer
- Zone level Volleyball Player